Guide to the Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, records
1846-1970
RU 819
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
58.25
(170 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, reports, financial records, student records and papers, photographs and memorabilia, grade books, clippings, class records, memoranda, notes, a copy of the 1944 charter and by-laws of the Board of Trustees of the Sheffield Scientific School and administrative files documenting the history and operations of the Sheffield Scientific School and relate to virtually every aspect of its activities.
Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 31-A (YRG 31-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Sheffield Scientific School.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Sheffield Scientific School, like the Graduate School, had its origins in the Department of Philosophy and the Arts established in 1847. It was given its name by the Yale Corporation in 1861 in recognition of the support of Joseph Earl Sheffield of New Haven who not only gave the first building but also provided funds for its equipment and development. Subsequently he made other gifts and finally bequeathed to a corporation, the Board of Trustees of the Sheffield S cientific School, a substantial endowment which was to be held and adninistered by the Trustees for the benefit of the natural, physical, and mathematical sciences in Yale University.
Sheffield was one of the first schools of higher education in the United States to devote its curriculum specifically to scientific training. The School played an important part in the evolution of American higher learning from the strict classical model of education t o a curriculum which encompassed a liberal scientific education.
The faculty of the School conducted graduate as well as undergraduate courses i n the sciences and engineering until 1919 when the former were discontinued. In 1932, engineering instruction was transferred to the newly organized Yale School of Engineering. In 1945 Sheffield resumed its original function of teaching at the graduate level. Under the general administration of the Graduate School, its faculty furnished instruction to graduate students in the sciences and mathematics who were M.A. and Ph.D. candidates. In 1956 the School's functions were absorbed by the Graduate School. The Directors of Sheffield Scientific School were: George Jarvis Brush, 1872-1898; Russell Henry Chittenden, 1898-1922; Charles Hyde Warren, 1922-1945; Edmund Ware Linnott, 1945-1956.
For further information see History of the Sheffield Scientific School of Yale University, 1846-1922 by Russell H. Chittenden (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1928).
1846 Yale establishes professorships of Agricultural Chemistry and Applied Chemistry "for the purpose of giving instruction to graduates and others not members of the undergraduate classes"
1847 "a School of Applied Chemistry" is embraced within the newly created Department of Philosophy and the Arts
1852 authorization of the Bachelor of Philosophy degree to be awrded by the Department of Philosophy and the Arts professorship of Civil Engineering established the Yale School of Engineering is organized under William A. Norton
1853-1854 Science (School of Applied Chemistry) and engineering (School of Engineering) courses are independent, but classed together in the catalogue under "the aegis of a non-existent institution"- the Yale Scientific School
1856 "Proposed Plan for a complete organization of the School of Science" and "Appeal in Behalf of the Yale Scientific School, with an Index": fundraising pamphlets issued
1858 Joseph Earl Sheffield donates funds and property on the northeast comer of Grove and Prospect Streets to the Scientific School
1860-1932 Engineering courses are offered in the Scientific School
1860 degree in Civil Engineering established degree of Doctor of Philosophy from the Scientific School established
1861 Yale Scientific School becomes the Sheffield Scientific School in recognition of the continuous generosity of Joseph Earl Sheffield
1863 the Sheffield Scientific School, through an Act of the Connecticut General Assembly, begins to receive the income from the Land Grant Fund of the State
1866 courses in Mining and Metallurgy announced "Public Lectures to Mechanics " instituted, later known as the "Sheffield Lectures", given for 45 years
1870 First Yale Scientific Expedition organized by Professor Othniel Marsh
1871 Articles of Incorporation of the Board of Trustees of the Sheffield Scientific School drawn up a t the suggestion of Joseph Earl Sheffield. Board to consist of nine directors including the Governor of Connecticut, the President of Yale University, the Chairman of the Trustees of the Peabody Museum and at least three professors in the Sheffield Scientific School
1872-1898 George Jarvis Brush, Director of the Sheffield Scientific School
1877 Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station established on a permanent basis by the Connecticut General Assembly with one of its Board of Control to be elected by the Trustees of the Sheffield Scientific School
1893 The Connecticut General Assembly passes an Act making Storrs Agricultural College the Land Grant College of Connecticut. Damages amounting to $154,604.45 were paid to the University and became a part of the permanent funds of the Sheffield Scientific School
1897 Semi-centennial celebration of the Sheffield Scientific School
1898-1922 Russell Henry Chittenden, Director of the Sheffield Scientific School
1905 Pierson-Sage Square property acquired for development of University laboratories
1913 land purchased at East Lyme for a field engineering camp
1916 "Students in the Sheffield Scientific School who are able to comply with the entrance requirements of the School of Medicine may combine their College and Medical courses, entering the School of Medicine at the beginning of their third College year"
1918 Voted "that in the opinion of the Corporation, the reasons which led to the establishment and maintenance of a course of 'Selected Studies in language, literature, history and Natural and Social Sciences' under the administration of the Faculty of the Sheffield Scientific School are no longer valid"
1918-1919 graduate courses are transferred to the Graduate School general reorganization of the educational structure of Yale University. Three year "Select" course at the Shef f ield Scientific School eliminated. A four year course of study "for students who wished to undertake the professional study of science and engineering" established
1919-1945 only undergraduate courses taught at the Sheffield Scientific School
1922 first award of the degree of Bachelor of Science to the graduating class of the Sheffield Scientific School
1922-1945 Charles Kyde Warren, Dean
1932-1962 the School of Engineering re-established. Sheffield Scientific School engineering courses transferred to the new school
1945 the Sheffield Scientific School resumes its original function of graduate level instruction in science. Undergraduate courses for a Bachelor of Science transferred t o Yale College. Undergraduate courses for a Bachelor of Science in industrial administration transferred to the School of Engineering
1945-1956 Edmund Ware Sinnott, Director (also Dean of the Graduate School, 1950-1956)
1947 Centennial celebration of the Sheffield Scientific School
1956 termination of the Sheffield Scientific School as an active school although the Board of Trustees still exists to oversee the Sheffield Scientific School property and meet legal requirements. Yale University Provost becomes Chairman of the Board. Faculty is defined as teachers of science to graduate students under the Division of Science
1967 North Sheffield Hall (1872-1873) and Winchester Hall (1892) removed to provide site for a new laboratory
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes, reports, financial records, student records and papers, photographs and memorabilia, grade books, clippings, class records, memoranda, notes, a copy of the 1944 charter and by-laws of the Board of Trustees of the Sheffield Scientific School and administrative files documenting the history and operations of the Sheffield Scientific School and relate to virtually every aspect of its activities.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in eleven series and subsequesnt accessions: I. Trustees and Governing Board Records, 1871-1967. II. Faculty Minutes, circa 1852-1945. III. Administrative Records, 1864-1956. IV. Financial, Legal, and Property Records, 1846-1969. V. Silliman Lectures. VI. Student Life, 1901-1949. VII. Student Papers, 1877-1909. VIII. Engineers Club, 1895-1918. IX. Class Records, 1869-1969. X. Photographs and Memorabilia, circa 1848-1951. XI. Class Registers, Lists, and Grade Books, 1848-1951.
Appendix: Selected List of Correspondence in the Russell Henry Chittenden Records
Abbott, Mather Alrnon (1874-1934)
Abbott, Wilbur Cortez (1869-1947)
Adams, John Chester (1874-1952)
Andrew, Abram Piat t (1873-1936)
Bailie, Earle C.
Baker, Newton Diehl (1871-1937)
Baldwin, Simeon (1884-1943)
Bardon, Clint on Lloyd (1867-1937)
Barney, Samuel Eben (1859-1940
Barron, Edmun D.
Bateman, Alan Mora (1888-1971)
Bates, Lindon Wallace (1883-1915)
Beatty, J. C.
Bedell, William V.
Beers, George Merson (18651947)
Benedict, Francis Gano (1870-1957)
Berard, Samuel John (1875-1972)
Black, W .Ma
Bozell, H.V.
Brandeis, Louis Dembitz (1856-1941)
Breckenridge, Lester Paige (1858-1940)
Brooks, Charles Franklin (18914958)
Brown, Ernest William (1866-1938)
Browning, Philip Embury (1866-1938)
Buell, Llewellyn Morgan
Bumstead, Henry Andrews (1870-1920)
Campbell, George Ashley (1 870-1954)
Chittenden, Russell Henry (1856-1943)
Clark, William Andrews (1839-1 925)
Clarke, Charles Cameron (1861-1935)
Coe, Wesley Roswell (1869-1960)
Corbin, William Herbert (1864-1945)
Corcoran, James A.
Corwin, Robert Nelson (1864-1944)
Craig, Charles F. (1872-1950)
Crawford, J.B.
Cross, Wilbur Lucius (1862-1948)
Curtiss, Henry Tomlinson (1888-1928)
Dana, Edward Salisbury (1849-1935)
Danford, Robert Melville (1879-1974)
Day, George Parmly (1876-1959)
Dean, Arthur Lyman (1878-1952)
deForest, Lee (1873-1961)
deForest Lectureship 1922-1923
deFores t Radiobook Collect ion
Doremus, A. T.
Drew, Mrs. Mary
Edsall, Davf d Linn (1869-1945)
Eisenhart, L.P.
English, Edwin Holt (1851-1899)
Espenschei d, Lloyd
Evans, Alexander William (1868-1959)
Farnam, Henry Walco tt (1853-1933)
Farwell, S.E.
Fisher, Irving (1867-1947)
Fisher, Richard Thornton (1876-1934)
Flagg, Stanley G., Jr.
Furst, Clyde fu ow man) (1873-1931)
Gantt, HenryLaurence (1861-
Gillespie, W.C.
Grahlfs, F.L.
Greenway, James Cowan (187 7-1976)
Gregory, Herbert Emes t (1869-1952)
Griffin, William Vincent (1886-1958)
Guernsey, Nathaniel Taylor (1857-1 934)
Hadley, Arthur lhining (1856-1930)
Hammond, Edward Sanford (1893-1972)
Harrison, Ross Granville (1870-1959)
Hartwell, John Augus tus (1869-1940)
Haverneyer, Loomis (1886-1971)
Heald, Daniel Addison (1889-1945)
Henderson, Yandell (1873-1944)
Herr, Edwin Musser (1860-1932)
Hibbert,Harold (1877-
Hflles, Charles Dewey (1867-1949)
Holt, Henry Gilbert (1887-1974)
Hooper, S.C.
Hoover, Herbert Clark (1874-1964)
Hovey, O t i s E l l i s (1864-1941)
Hoyle, R. E l i DuBose (1851-1921)
Hull, Albert Wallace (1880-1966)
Hurlburt, Everett Bradley (1873-1971)
Internal Revenue Department
Irving, John Duer (1874-1918)
Jeffcott, Robert Crawford (1878-1961)
Jenks, Jeremiah Whipple (1856-1929)
Johnson, Emory Richard (1864-1950)
Johnson, Frederic Blair,. (1876-1951)
Johnson, Treat Baldwin (1875-1947)
Jones, Frederick Scheetz (1862-1944)
Keller, Albert Gal loway (1874-1956)
Kelley, Edward B. (1896-1972)
Kennedy, Julian (1852-1932)
Kenyon, Miss Irene S.
Keogh, Andkew (1869-1953)
King, Willard Vinton (1868-1955)
Kirby, Richard Shelton (1874-1964)
Kirkham, William Barri (1882-1969)
Lavis, Fred
Leach, Henry Goddard (1880- )
Lippitt, Henry (1886-1974)
Lockwood, Edwin Hoyt (1866-1930)
Luce, Henry Robinson (1898-196 7)
Luquiens, Frederick B l i s s (1875-1940)
McClelland, James Farley (1878-1955)
McCormick, Vance Criswell (1872-1946)
McDonnell, John Vincent (1889-1926)
McHargue, We R.
McI lhenny, John A.
Maltbie, Milo R.
Mansfield, Burton (1856-1932)
Mathewson, Champion Herbert (1881-1972)
Meeker, Royal (1873-1953)
Mendel, Lafayette Benedict (1872-1935)
Mendel, William (1898-1950)
Merritt, Alfred Kindred (1866-1943)
Millikan, Robert Andrews (1868-1953)
Morecroft, John
Morrow, F.J.
Motor Vehicles, 1917
Mullins, Frederic Parson (1890-1964)
Murray, EeBI
Needham, Charles Kinney (1848-1928)
Nelson, Frank Thayer (1887-1970)
Nettleton, George Henry (1874-1959)
Nichols, George Elwood (1882-1939)
Noyes, Anna G.
Osborn, Minott Augur (1884-1959)
Osgood, William Fogg (1864-1943)
Osler, Sir William, bart. (18494919)
Ostrander, Harry Judd
Oviatt, Edwin (Sidney) (1874-1955)
Owen, Robert Latham (1856-1947)
Owyang, Earl C,
Page, Edward Day (1856-1918)
Page Lectures, 1917-1918
Pirsson, Louis Valentine (1860-1919)
Pratt, Francis Cole (1867-19 30)
Rand, Charles Frederic (1856-1927)
Randolph, Francis Fitz (1889-1973)
Ray, David H.
Raymond, Rossiter Worthington (1840-1918)
Reed. Edward B l i s s. (1872-1940)
Rees, Robert Irwin (1 871-1936)
Rettger, Leo Frederick (1874-1953)
Rice, Frank James (1869-1917)
Roe, Joseph Wickham (1871-1960)
Ropes, James Hardy (1866-1933)
Schlesinger, Frank (1873-1943)
Scholarships, 1919-1921
Schuchert, Charles (1858-1942)
Schwab, John Chris topher (1865-1916)
Scott, Charles Felton (1864-1944)
Sedgwick, William Thompson (1855-1921)
Seward, Herbert Lee (1885-1966)
Shanklin, William Arnold (1862-1924)
Shepard, Norman Arthur
Simpson, E. Ridgely
Slaughter, Nugent H.
Smith, Harrison Braxton (1889-1966)
Smith, Percey Franklyn (1867-1956)
Smith, Theobald (1859-1934)
Squire, Walter (1913-1951)
Squires, George 0.
Standard O i l Company
Steams, Alfred Ernest (1871-1949)
Stetson, George Albert (1889-1959)
Stilwell, Katharine Me (Mrs. Arthur A,)
Stoeckel, Robbins B. (1872-1951)
Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (1874-1958)
Stone, Warren Sanford (1860-1925)
S trathcona Scholarship
Stratton, W.S.
Strong, Richard Pearson (1872-1948)
Swain, George Fillmore (185 7-1931)
Taft, Horace Dutton (1861-1943)
Taft, William Howard (1857-1930)
Taggart, Arthur Fay (1884-1959)
Taussig, Frank William (1859-1940)
Taylor, Andrew Sandford (1867-1 949)
Taylor, Frederick Winslow (1856-1915) -
Thomas, Eustace
Thompson, Maud Robinson (Mrs. Elbridge Blish)
Tiffany, Louis Comfort (1848-1933)
Tilden, Charles Joseph (1873-1959)
Tilson, John Quillin (1866-1958)
Todd, David (1855-1939)
Tracy, John Clayton (1869-1955)
Trumbull, Frank (1858-1920)
Turner, Hubert Mrchael
Tuttle, Howard Beecher (1863-1933)
Underhill, Frank P e l f (1877-1932)
Untermyer, Samuel (1858-1940)
Vanderlip, Frank Arthur (1864-1937
Verwom, Max (1863-192?)
Vreeland, Herbert Harold (1856-1945)
Ward, Freeman (1879-1943)
Warner, Russell Gillette (1892-1965)
Warren, Charles Hyde (1896-1950)
Waters, Everett Oyfer (1890-1926)
Watrous, George Dutton (1858-1940)
Weld, Louis Dwight Karvell (1882-1946)
Welldon, Samuel A.
Wells, Horace Lemuel (1855-1924)
Westinghouse, George (1846-1914)
Wheeler, Lynde Phelps (1874-1959)
Whipple, Henry S tacy (1855-1936)
White, Benjamin (1879-1938)
Whit temore, James K e f sey
Wilcox, Lucian Thames (1885-1971)
Willcox, Walter Francis (1861- )
Williams, Edward Gilbert (1865-1942)
Wilson, Woodrow (1856-1924)
Winslow, Charles-Edward Amory (187 -1957)
Winternitz, M i l t on Charles (1885-1959)
Wittig, Gustav Frederick (1876-1950)
Wohlenberg, Walter Jacob (1888-1956)
Woodruff, Lorand Loss (1879-1947)
Woodward, George (Stanley) (1863-1952)
Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury (1852-1929)
Worcester, Dean Conant (1866-1924)
Wright, Henry Parks (1839-1918)
Wright, Thomas Goddard (1885-1919)
Yamagawa, Kenjiro (1854-1931)
Yergason, Henry Bingham Bartlett (1876-1919)
Yow, Jeme Tien
Yudkin, Arthur Meyer (1892-195 7)
Zautner, Norman George (1893-1973)
Zee, Zai-Ziang (1882-1969)
Zeleny, John (1872-1951)
Custodial History
Accession 2012-A-077, Board of Trustees records, were transferred by Lourdes O'Neil Haynes, Office of the Vice President and General Counsel, 2012.
Silliman Lecturers, 1902-1980
1902-1903 Joseph John Thomson
1903-1904 Charles Scott Sherrington
1904-1905 Emest Rutherford
1905-1906 Omitted
1906-1907 Walter Nernst
1907-1908 William Bateson
1908-1909 Albrecht Penck
1909-1910 William Wallace Campbell
1910-1911 Svante August Arrhenius
1911-1912 Max Verworn
1912-1913 William Osler
1913-1914 Frank Dawson Adams, Arthur Philemon Coleman, Joseph Paxson Iddings, Waldemar Lindgren, William Diller Matthew, Frederick Leslie Ransome, William North Rice, Charles Doolittle Walcott
1914-1916 Omitted
1916-1917 John Scott Baldane
1917-1918 Joseph Barrell, Wesley Roswell Coe, Edward Salisbury Dana, Harry Ward Foote, William Ebenezer Ford, George Lincoln Goodale, Herbert Ernest Gregory, Richard Swann Lull, Leigh Page, Louis Valentine Pirsson, Charles Schuchert, George Otis Smith, Horace Lemael Wells
1918-1919 Omitted
1919-1920 Jacques Solomon Hadamard
1920-1921 Franz Cumont
1921-1922 Clemens Pirquet
1922-1923 August Krogh
1923-1924 Niels Bohr
1924-1925 Thomas Hunt Morgan
1925-1926 Gilbert Newton Lewis
1926-1927 Emes t Clayton Andrews
1927-1928 Lawrence Joseph Henderson
1928-1930 Omitted
1930-1931 Heinrich Wieland
1931-1932 Owen Willans Richardson
1932-1933 Omitted
1933-1934 Reginald Aldworth Daly, Hans Spemann
1934-1935 Omitted
1935-1936 Edwin Powell Hubble
1936-1937 David Meredith Seares Watson
1937-1938 Omitted
1938-1939 Albert Charles Chibnall
1939-1940 Richard Benedikt Goldschmidt
1940-1946 Omitted
1946-1947 Edwin Joseph Cohn
1947-1948 George Wells Beadle, Emest Orlando Lawrence, Linus Carl Pauling, Wendell Meredith Stanley
1948-1949 Ross Granville Harrison
1949-1950 Enrico Ferrni
1950-1951 Harold Clayton Urey
1951-1952 Hans Pettersson
1952-1953 Carl Ferdinand Cori, John Ray Dunning, Chauncey Guy Suits
1953-1954 Ragnar Granit
1954-1955 Kenneth Wartenbe Spence
1955-1956 Omitted
1956-1957 Glenn Theodore Seaborg
1957-1958 Omitted
1958-1959 Theodosius Dobzhansky (qv)
1959-1960 William Walden Rubey
1960-1961 Rene Jules Dubos
1961-1962 Omitted
1962-1963 Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar
1963-1964 Louis Seymour Bazet t Leakey (qv),Sir Alexander Todd
1964-1965 Robert Sanderson Mulliken
1965-1966 William Albert Hugh Rushton
1966-1967 Omitted
1967-1968 Jacob Bronowski
1968-1969 Joshua Lederberg
1969-1970 Walter William Bishop, Arthur L. Bloom, Wallace S. Broecker, Paul E. Damon, Willi Dansgaard, George H. Denton, K.O. Emery, Cesare Emiliani, William Maurice Ewing, William Re Farrand, C.C. Flerow, Kenneth Hunkins, John Imbrie, Kazimierz Kowalski, Barrie C. McDonald, Henry William Menard, Jr., Stephen C. Porter, Minze Stuiver, T. van der Hammen, H.E. Wright, Jr.
1970-1971 Steven Kuffler
1971-1975 Omitted
1975-1976 Francois Jacob
1976-1977 Allan Cox
1977-1978 Steven Weinberg, Lyman Spitzer, 3rd.
1978-1979 Arthur Kornberg
1979-1980 Anne McLaren
General
Chang, Tatsemg, "An Outline of the Theory of Electromagnetic Waves" 22pp, box 89, folder 960 was reported missing in April 2015.
Luker, Herbert, "On the Anatomy of Three West Indian Epiphytes" 9pp, box 90, folder 995 was reported missing in April 2015.
Kendall, C.H., "The Electromagnetic Theory of Light" 30pp 1903 box 90, folder 985 was reported missing in April 2015.
Allen, Wyatt H., "Electrical Units and Standards" 29pp, box 89, folder 946 was reported missing April 2015
College students -- Societies, etc.; Engineering -- Study and teaching; Lectures and lecturing; Science students; Science -- Societies, etc.; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Photographs; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
- Trustees and Governing Board Records, 1871-1967; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains the records of the Sheffield Scientific School's policy setting and administrative bodies - the Board of Trustees, responsible for overseeing property and finances, and the Governing Board, responsible for curriculum development, faculty appointments and other academic matters.
  The Trustees Records 1871-1967 is comprised of minutes of the Executlve Committee meetings and the Board of Trustees meetings, financial papers, including Treasurer's reports, Auditor's reports, funds and bequest materlal and correspondence.
  The Governing Board Records 1872-1956 consists of a complete set of minutes. Included in these volumes are recommendations for faculty appointments and promotions, committee reports, curriculum approval and recommendations of candidates for degrees.
  The materials in Series I are grouped into sections by administrative unit: the Board of Trustees, the Executive Committee and the Governing Board. The materials within each section are arranged chronologically.
  - Trustees Records
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees Meetings (bound volume), 1871 July 10 - 1923 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee Meetings, 1902 December 8 - 1923 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee Meetings, 1924 February 18 - 1943 August 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees Meetings (bound volume), 1924 September 16 - 1945 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee Meetings, 1943 October 8 - 1957 June 12 (Box 2)
  - Records of the Executive Committee Meetings
    - Agenda, financial statements, reports, 1945 February 5 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Agenda, correspondence re: funds, reports, 1949 Apr19 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Agenga, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1950 June 8 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Agenda, correspondence, financial statements, minutes, 1953 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Agenda, correspondence, financial statements, minutes, 1954 May 6 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Agenda, financial statements, 1955 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1963 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Agenda, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1964 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Agenda, correspondence, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1965 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1966 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Records of the Board of Trustees Meetings
    - Agenda, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1945 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Agenda, financial statements, reports, 1946 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Agenda, financial statements, reports, 1946 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Agenda, financial statements, reports, 1947 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, minutes, treasurer's report, 1947 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, minutes, treasurer's report, 1948 October 22 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, 1949 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, treasurer's report, 1950 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, treasurer's report, 1951 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Auditor's report, financial statements, securities list, treasurer's report, 1952 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 26)